我一定得讲话吗?
Am I gonna have to give a speech?
你是发行人 你说不行吗?
You're the publisher. Can't you do it?
我只能替你暖场
I can warm them up.
在新书巡回宣传展开前abc你一定要克服对公开演说的恐惧
But you are gonna have to get over thisabcfear of public speaking before the book tour.
各位 请大家注意 谢谢
Tim has a few words to say.
Tim 想说几句话
There you go, tim. They're warmed up.
轮到你了 大家都等着呢
Well, what do youabcsay at a time like this?
这种场合你该说什么?
Seriously,what do you say?
说真的 你该说什么?
You could thank everyone for coming.
你可以谢谢大家赏光出席
Thank you, nick.
谢谢 Nick 实际上我一直感谢Nickabc他不仅是个笔锋犀利的编辑
Actually,I'm always thanking nick, a manabcnot only famousr his ruthless editor's pen,
更有着驾驭疯狂作家的无比耐心
but his patientabchand-holding of crazy authors.
也许你认为出版了三本小说后abc我的信心会有所增加 但是...
You'd think that after three novels, I'dabcstart to develop a little confidence, but...
有今天这本书 你的信心会越来越足
For a book like this, weabcare happy to supply the confidence.
新书大卖
Best-seller.
- 这是不可能的abc- 什么?
- Well,that's not gonna hapn.abc- What?
拜托 短篇小说赚不了钱
Come on. Shorstories don't make money.
早在1908年 短篇小说就不能赚钱了
Short stories weren'tabcmaking money back in 1908.
除非你是数盲 才以为abc它会跟小说一样畅销
You'd haveto be mathematically illiterateabcto think they'd do as well as a novel.
好了 Nick 以免有人受伤害abc你不要再喝香槟了
Okay, nick, let's step away from theabcchampagne before somebody gets hurt.
你和我一样 为这本书劳心劳力
You slaved over thisabcbook right next to me.
如果这注定了是个赔本货abcNorthrop为什么要出版它?
Why would northrop even publish itabcif it's only going to tank?
你不知道 你是我们的明星级作家吗?
Have you failed toabcnotice you're our star author?
显然Elaine不想得罪你
Obviously, elaineabcwouldn't want to offend you.
甜心
Uh, honey.
对不起 我不知道我为什么要这样说
I-I'm sorry. I don't--Iabcdon't know why I said that.
他在开玩笑
He's joking.
Nick和所有人一样abc深知你所从事的是艺术
Nick knows as well as anyoneabcwhat you have done is art.
用纸折小动物也是艺术abc但不能指望用它来赚钱
So is folding paper into animal shapes, butabcyou don't expect to make a living off it.
你到底有什么毛病?
Hat the hell is wrong with you?
你真以为 一个一年换了10个助手
You really think someone who goesabcthrough ten assistants a year
而且不给自己孩子回电话的人
and doesn't return herabcown children's phone calls
会关心美国短篇小说的境况?
would give a damn about the stateabcof the american short story?
求求你 别说了
Please, be quiet.
我想有点不对劲
I think something's wrong.
书名就是一个错误
That title was a mistake too.
你以为人们会拿你跟塞林格比?abc还是趁早断了这念头吧
People are gonna compare you to salinger, and,abcboy, are you gonna come up short on that one.
甜心!
Honey!
打911! 来人啊! 救命!
Call 911. Help! We need help!
Cameron从急诊室拿来了这个
Cameron brought this up from the E.R.
看来不像是个友谊手镯
Doesn't look like a friendship bracelet.
是Phineas Gage
It's phineas gage.
史上最著名的医学案例
The most famous caseabcstudy in medical history.
你想告诉我 这个病人被一根abc铁路道钉戳穿了他的前额叶?
You're telling me this patient got a railroadabcspike drilled through his frontal lobe?
不 没有外部创伤abc但他的额叶功能失控
No. No trauma, but he doesabchave frontal lobe disinhibition.
和Gage一样
Just like gage.
Gage受伤后变了一个人abc变得冲动 好斗
Gage was a different person afterabcthe spike. Argumentative. Impulsive.
而我们的病人喝了葡萄酒后变了个人
Whereas our guy became aabcdifferent person after chardoay.
他入院时很镇定
He was sober when they brought him in.
有过鼻出血和昏阙症状
There's also theabcnosebleed, the collapse.
- MRI有发现吗?abc- 没有
- Mri show anything?abc- Nothing.
好 这就好玩了
Good.*****
那么说肿瘤觉得自己待的社区不够带劲
So the tumor's not inabcthe cool neighborhood.
想发展到相邻的社区去
It's cool neighborhood adjacent.
特定位置的鼻腔内肿瘤abc可能侵蚀大脑 导致脑损伤
A well-placed tumor in the nasal cavityabceroding into the brain could do the damage.
在Phineas的鼻子置入摄像头abc看有什么发现
Go stick a scope up phineas'sabcnose. See what you find.
爹地 如果你再把牌告诉我abc我就会一直赢下去了
Daddy, I'm always gonna win if youabckeep telling me what your cards are.
我只有在...挠你痒痒时才会告诉你
Well, then suppose I tellabcyou... while I tickle you.
Greenwald先生 我是Taub医生abc这位是Kutner医生
Mr. Greenwald, I'm dr.abcTaub. Is is dr. Kutner.
我们又得给你做检查了 很抱歉
We're here for anotherabctest. Sorry about that.
你一点都不抱歉
You don't look sorry.
无意冒犯 但你看起来很是高兴
Um, no offense. Althoughabcyou do look kind of cheerful.
让人有点毛骨悚然abc我不想找个对我生病感到兴奋的医生?
It's a little creepy. Should I want aabcdoctor who's excited about how sick I am?
- 我没有--abc- 我们要把这个放入你的鼻子 看有什么问题
- I'm not-- - We're going to put thisabcup your nose, scan for any problems.
我可以向你保证abc我们一点不兴奋
I can assure you that we areabcmpletely unexcited abo that.
打扰一下 甜心
Excuse me, sweetie.
她有听觉处理障碍
She has an auditoryabcprocessing disability.
Marika-Beleekaabc你得先下床一阵子
Marika-beleeka, youabchave to get off the bed.
可能会有轻微不适
This might be slightly uncomfortable
宝贝 介意我走开一阵吗?
Honey, do you mind if I step out?
我得确认一下乳癌步行筹款的安排
I have to make sure the final arrangementsabcare in place for the breast cancer walk.
好 你去吧
Yeah, you do that.
留下我一个人充好汉 看着这家伙abc把三尺长的塑料棍塞进我的鼻子
I'll pretend to be macho while a guyabcstuffs three feet of plastic up my nose.
要是是你的鼻子倒好了
It's too bad it's not your nose.
有更大的活动空间
Lots more room to maneuver.
我想可以等上十分钟 再去处理步行的事
I guess the walk can wait ten minutes.
在一个理性世界里abc根本该无限期推迟
Or in a sensible rld, even longer.
让交通堵塞六小时对abc治疗乳癌有何裨益?
Just how does tying up trafficabcfor six hours stop breast cancer?
你知道的 人们会捐钱--
You know how itabcworks.People donate--
何不干脆花六小时盖收容中心?
Why not spend six hours buildingabchouses for habitat for humanity?
还是说不能同时帮助两个群体?
Or is it wrong to help twoabcgroups of people at once?
我打赌肯定有人既患乳癌又无家可归
I bet there are those whoabchave breast cancer and no home.
这是我的工作 Nickabc你去年也参加步行了
It's my job, nick. Youabcwalked yourself last year.
纯粹为了支持你
To be supportive.
因为如果我不这么做abc你就不会和我做爱
And because I knew you wouldn'tabchave sex with me if I didn'T.
我要去打电话了
I'm gonna make my call.
尽管去吧
Make this go away.
上帝 这鼻子真大
God, that honker reallyabcis huge, isn't it?
星期三晚上
Wednesday night.
无敌蓝魔对阵焚化之王
Low-wn-blue-meanieabcversus the incinerator.
我去不了
I can'T.
我再说一遍 无敌蓝魔--
Let meabcrephra.Low-down-blue-meanie--
我能听懂怪物卡车的代号
I understand monster truck code.
你能听懂"去不了"吗?
Do you understand "can't"?
在"无敌蓝魔"后出现就不懂了
Not when it followsabc"low-down-blue-meanie."
星期二晚上是世界末日吗?abc不然星期三--
Is the world coming to an endabctuesday night? Otherwise, wednesday--
好了 不是"去不了"abc其实是"不想去"
All right, it's not "can'T."abcIt's "don't want to."
因为我不喜欢怪物卡车
The fact is I just donabclike monster trucks.
- 不 你喜欢abc- 不 我不喜欢
- Yes, you do.abc- No, I don't.
你一向喜欢怪物卡车
You've always liked monster trucks.
不 是你一向很喜欢abc我只能被迫忍受
No, you've always likedabcthem. I've tolered them.
实话说 当我看着这帮轰隆隆的怪物abc在沙丘上横冲直撞 把汽车房屋碾碎
Seriously, I can only watch so many hyped-upabcdune buggies crush so many motor homes
我恨不得逃去听"波西米亚人"
without feeling theabcurge to go see la boheme.
虽然我也很讨厌歌剧
And I hate opera too.
你在隐瞒什么?
What are you hiding?
我没有隐瞒abc我大声且自豪地说出了这番话
I'm not hiding it. I'mabcsaying it loud and proud.
- 永别了怪物卡车abc- 不是鼻癌
- Death to monster trucks.abc- No nasal cancer.
而且如果我们的病人再这么abc口没遮拦地说出脑里想的每件事
D no marriage either if our patient keepsabcsaying everything that comes into his head
他的婚姻就要完蛋了
without regard for the consequences.
我还以为你是这个物种的唯一余孽
You always led me toabcbelieve you were one of a kind.
幸而变混蛋只是他的暂时症状
Luckily jerkiness is aabctemporary condition for this guy.
不 才不是
No, it's not.
你也许能抑制他把话说出来的冲动
We may be able to fix his impulseabcto say his thoughts out loud,
但无法抑制他心里这么想
but he always gonna beabcthe guy who thinks them.
但他至少不会说出来
But he's also gonna betheabcguy who doesn't say them.
如果他可以终身维持abc这个好好先生的形象
If he spent his whole lifeabcconstructing this nice guy persona,
跟他本来就是好人有什么区别?
isn't that as much who heabcreally is as anything else?
你当然这么说 你多会装腔作势
You would argue that.abcYou're all persona.
我同意Wilsonabc这家伙就是哈利波特
I agree with wilson.abcThis guy's aarry potter.
分院帽根据Harry的本性abc准备把他分到斯莱特林学院(象征野心)
The sorting hat was going to put harryabcin slytherin based on his nature.
他拒绝了 所以最后去了格兰芬多学院abc(象征勇敢)
He refus,so he ended up in gryffindor.
选择改变命运
Through choice.
他的脑子某个地方损伤了abc把它找出来
There's damage somewhereabcin his brain. Find it.
你确定你听明白了?
Are you sure you understand?
不 我撒谎了 只是我根本不能撒谎
No, I'm lying. Except I can'T.
你问我问题
You ask questions.
当我回答时 你观察我脑部活动abc看哪里出了问题
While I talk,you look at my brainabcactivity to see where it's screwed up.
然后把有问题的地方切下来检查
Then you're gonna cut the screwedabcup part out to test it.
听起来很可怕abc但不至于高深到无法理解
It's depressing,butabcit's not rocket science.
我想他明白了
I think he understands.
我无意如此粗鲁
I don't mean to be abrasive.
但幻想你裸体的样子让我很兴奋
Especially since you'reabcsuch a pleasure to image naked.
- 再次道歉abc- 没关系
- Ain, sorry.abc- It's okay.
谢谢你的体谅
Thank you for understanding.
但我还是会上你
I'd do you, though.
- 真的对不起 我控制不了abc- 没关系
- Really, my apologies. This stuff just comes out.abc- It's okay.
House呼我
House paged.
哇 我恨不得在她胸部放上abc乳糖和樱桃 然后马上干她
Whoa, I would do her in a minuteabcwith fudge and a cherry on top.
能不能替我向这位女士解释下abc我实在是非常抱歉--
Would someone please explain to thisabcwoman? There's only so many apologies--
他患有额叶功能失控
He hafrontal lobe disinhibition.
我在这位医生面前已经出过糗了
I've already embarrassed myselfabcwith one doctor,
此刻我正想象你们俩躺在一张abc特大号的床上 天花板安着镜子
whom I am at this moment imaginin with you inabca king-sized bed with a mirror on the cling.
实在非常抱歉
I am so, so sorry.
要是我不能同时拥有你们俩abc你毫无疑问是我的第一选择
But if I couldn't have both of you together,abcyou definitely would be my first choice.
House在哪里?
Where's house?
我实在无法忽视这头大象abc(房间里的大象 喻显而易见的事物)
It's like trying not toabcthink of an elephant.
我不是说你是大象abc你的胸部是人类的--
Not that you're an elephant.Yourabcbreasts, in fact,are all homo sapiens--
House不在这里
House isn't here.
如果他看不到这场好戏abc就不会把我呼来了--
Oh, he wouldn't have paged meifabche couldn't watch and enjoy the--
你的屁股就像法拉利上的发动机
Your tush is like theabcpistons in a ferrari.
不用谢
You're welcome.
我得了什么好处要谢你?
That was for my benefit
- 你40岁了abc- 38
- You're 40 years old...abc- 38.
管理着偌大一家医院...
The administrator of a hospital...
- 我是医学院院长abc- 人们不会对你说实话
- Dean of medicine.abc- People don't get personal with you.
除了我以外 但你总以为我拿你开涮abc无视我的发言
Except for me,and you dismiss meabcas a jerk who's jerking you around.
但那家伙说出了真相
But that guy can only tell the truth.
他喜欢你的身材胜过一个性感小辣妹
And he prefers your body toabcthatof a smokin' young hottie.
那么说 这是你称赞abc我今天很好看的方式?
So that was your way ofabcsaying I look good day.
我的奉承一点没让你高兴吗?
You didn't get theabcslightest kick out of that?
别胡闹了 House
Don't be ridiculous,house.
我想让你知道 你的"发动机"是最棒的
I hope you know yourabcpistons are second to none.
没事 我不嫉妒Cuddy的发动机
I'm okay. I'm notabcjealous of cuddy's pistons.
开始基线活动扫描
Starting baseline activation.
你肯定? 你看起来不大高兴
You sure? You looked upset.
因为他说的话很恼人
What he was saying was obnoxious.
没有人说过你很迷人?
You've never been called attractive?
他没有说我迷人abc他只是把我当成意淫对象
He didn't call me attractive.abcHe cast me in his mental porno.
这正是迷人的定义abc就是说"你让我想入非非"
That's what attractive means. Itabcmeans "I'm attracted to you, sexually."
迷人也可以说是abc"我被你的人格魅力所吸引"
Attracted can also mean "I'm attractedabcto the whole package. To who you are."
轴向切面60有轻微上升
Slight elevation at transaxial 60.
有可能 但实际情况绝不会是这样abc这是女人想听的 不是男人所想的
It could. It never does. It's whatabcwomen choose to hear,not what men say.
实际上 稍微有点脑子的男人都会这么想
Actually,it's exactly what menabcsay if they have any brains.
好了 基线扫描可以了
All right, we have enough for a baseline.
哪些问题是随意的abc又是他不会介意我们知道的?
What can we ask him that's indiscreet,abcbut that he won't hate us for knowing?
Nick 你和妻子投了abc同一个总统候选人票吗?
Nick, do you vote theabcsame way as your wife?
上帝 没有
God, no.
好极了 最高点在30
Good. He's spiking at right?
她相信奥巴马那一套abc你们肯定以为我投共和党 对吧?
********
错了 我从不投票
Wrong. I secretly don't vote. Ever.
慢着 你46岁了 却从未投过票?
Wait, you're 46,and you've never voted?
当你用这种苛责的语调时abc你的声线变得不再迷人
Your voice isno longer attractiveabcto me with that note of disapproval.
但我相信会过去的
Although I'm sure that will pass.
你看 扣带回有一点没有发亮
Look at that. There's a spot in theabccingulategyrus that's not lighting up.
少了你这一票有什么分别?
One vote makes a difference?
-  虽然数理上不是abc-  好了 Nick 我们找到了
- Not mathematical true.abc- Okay, nick. We've got what we need.
我们不能做活检 太靠近脑干了
We can't biopsy that. It'sabctoo close to the brainstem.
可能是神经系统结节病abc至少是可治愈的
Could be neurosarcoidosis.abcAt least it's treatable.
我们给他类固醇 如果我们是对的abc病情会在半天内好转
So we give him steroids,and we're right, we shouldabcstart seng his symptoms improve within half a day.
你在看什么?
What are you looking at?
你要求平等民主的工作环境abc我觉得这极度性感
I find your strong attachment to aabcworking democracy to be extremely sexy.
油腔滑调
Ooh, you smooth talker.
你觉得我的鼻子很大么?
Do you think my nose is too big?
安啦 他还说我的态度轻佻呢abc你也不同意他的话 对吧?
Relax, he also implied my bedside manner wasabca lite off. You don't agree with that,right?
当然
No.
没人说过你的鼻子?abc你可是整容医生啊
No one's ever mentioned your noseabcbefore? You're a plastic surgeon.
- 他们说很合我脸型abc- 的确
- They tell meit suits my face.abc- It does.
也许这就是所谓的社会契约
Maybe. Maybe that'sabcjust the social contract.
你说我长得很好看abc我回敬说你是好人
You tell me I look great. Iabctell you you're a people person.
你如何才能得知真相?
How can you know the truth?
你可以要求别人说出真相
You could ask for the truth.
你觉得我的鼻子怎么样?abc请你告诉我真相
What do you think of my nose?abcPlease tell me the truth.
挺好 普通鼻子呗
It's fine. It's a nose.
证实了我的观点
Just oving a point.
这儿有人坐吗?
Anyone sitting here?
我扮演的角色坐着
Just my persona.
真奇怪 有人会揪着别人侮辱他的话不放
You know, it's amazingabcthe way people cling on to insults.
或者说他误以为别人侮辱他的话
Or what they think are insults.
那么说 这还不算侮辱?
So that wasn't an insult?
我不是说 你和我们的病人一样abc表面上 逼着自己对别人友善
I'm not suggesting that, like ourabcpatient, you're hiding a dark,
其实在甜蜜外衣底下abc隐藏着黑暗 刻薄的一面
sarcastic core beneath a candyabcshell of compulsive nicene.
我不会总是那么友善abc我对你就没有好脸色
I'm not always nice.abcI'm not nice to you.
因为你知道好脸色只会使我厌烦
Because you know nice bores me.
但对我还是很好
Hence, still nice.
我的意思是 你没有原则
No, I'm suggesting that you have no core.
你只是在做别人所期待的那个人
Yore what whoever you'reabcwith needs you to be.
好吧 我想这有点侮辱人了
Okay, I guess that could be insulting.
吊诡之处在于 为什么
The interesting question is why.
为什么你会认为 没有你充当救世主abc这个世界就会陷入混乱并最终毁灭?
Why do you thinkthe world will end in chaosabcand destruction if you're not there to save it?
因为我的父母把我送上abc飞往地球的火箭时 对我说:
Because when my parents put me in theabcrocket and sent me here, they said,
"James 你会在阳光下茁壮成长--"
"james, you will grow toabcmanhood under yellow sun--"
还有怪物卡车的事你为什么要撒谎?
And why'd you lie about monster trucks?
- 我没有abc- 我查了你的日程本
- I didn'T.abc- I checked your appointment bk.
你把明天晚上圈起来了abc但没有写要干什么
You got tomorrow nightmarked off, butabcyou didn't put down what you were doing.
就是说 你知道有人会偷看--
So you thought someoneabcmight look at e book--
我明天晚上约了Taub打短柄墙球
I'm playing racquet ball tomorrowabcnight with taub.
你为什么要隐瞒这个?
Why would you hide that?
因为这个世界得围着你转
Because the world revolves around you.
一旦我找别人玩 你就会abc跟踪我 还有去骚扰别人
I devote timeto anyone else, you'dabcend up stalking me and harassing them.
你说的一点不好玩似的
You say that as thoughabcit wouldn't be fun.
而且我不想戳着你的鼻子告诉你abc我们要去做的事你永远也做不了
And maybe I didn't want to rub your nose in theabcfact that we'd be doing so thing you can no longer do.
因为我要装好人
Because I'm nice.
不是说类固醇可以让他好转吗?
I thought you said thesteroidsabcwere gonna help him.
怎么--是他心脏的问题?
What--is itabchis heart?
心电图显示心脏没问题 是肾脏
Ekg says heart's fine.abcIt's gotta be the kidneys.
我必须给他做透析
I need to get him on dialysis.
他在做透析 情况稳定了
He's on dialysis,and he's stable.
我们知道这不是系统性硬化病
We know it's not systemic sclerosis.
嘿 大鼻子情圣
Hey, cyrano de berkowitz.
得了吧你
Let it go.
慢性淋巴细胞白血病可以解释abc脑子和肾脏的问题
Chronic lymphocytic leukemia couldabcexplain brain and kidney problems.
血检显示白血球正常
The cbc showed normal white blood cells.
你和Wilson打短柄墙球多久了?
So how long have you been ayingabcracquetball with wilson?
四五次吧
Four five times.
可能是糖尿病
Could be diabetes.
或者是先天性代谢紊乱
Or a congenal metabolic disorder.
先天性疾病通常不会等到46岁才发作
Cgenital disorders generally don'tabcwait till you're 46 to manifest.
他发育迟缓
So he's a late bloomer.
她女儿有神经损伤症状
His daughter has aabcneurological condition.
首先 Wilson在大学校队打的是网球abc而你是犹太人
First of all, wilson played tennis onabchis college team, and you ara jew.
你运动根本不行 跑到走廊头再回来abc我来计时
You're not athletic. Run the endabcof the hall and back. I'll time you.
Sandy Koufax也是犹太人abc(棒球明星)
Sandy koufax is jewish.
最棒的左手前投手
Greatest left-handedabcpitcher of all time.
你们犹太人就只有Sandy Koufax
Sandy koufax is all you jews go on about.
Sandy Koufax和大屠杀 过时了
Sandy koufax and theabcholocaust. Gets old.
有太多先天性疾病符合病征
There are dozens of congenitalabcconditions that fit our parameters.
我们没时间做基因测试
We can't spend time geneabctesting for all of 'em,
特别是猜测阶段
especially when we're onlyabcguessing it's congenital.
那么Z-击球 攻还是守?
Is a z-shot offensive or defensive?
都有
It's both.
你认为这是哄骗
You suspected that was a trick question.
也可以说都没有
But could have said neither.
糖尿病更讲得通
Diabetes makes more sense.
要精减到四十种可能
We can narrow the testingabcdown to 40 likely candidates.
检查外周神经损伤
Test for peripheral nerve damage.
他有脑损伤 不管怎么都会有abc外周神经损伤的
He's got brain damage. He's likely toabchave peripheral nerve damage no matter what the cause.
是 所以没让你去检查他
Yes, that's why weabcshould not test him for it.
去检查女儿
Test the daughter.
Kutner去做神经测试
Kuer runs the nerve test.
Taub 糖尿病也有可能
Taub, you might beabcright about the diabetes.
别给他晚饭了 去做葡萄糖耐量试验
Take supper away from our patientabcand run a glucose tolerance test.
噢 护士都忙坏了
Oh, and the nursesabchave been working so hard.
你还是亲自去抽血吧
You can do the blood draws yourself.
每两小时就得抽一次
They have to be done every couple hours.
你这是惩罚我 因为你嫉妒abc我和你最好的朋友出去玩
You're punishing me because you're jealousabcthat I'm spending time with your best friend.
这也太小气了
That would be petty.
我惩罚你 是因为你和我的好朋友abc一起骗我
I'm punishing you because now you'veabcjoined my best friend in lying to me.
你准备招供的时候叫我
Let me know when you'reabcready to confess everything.
这个有可能热 有可能冷
The can become either hot or cold.
当你感到不适的时候就告诉我
As soon as it stts to feelabcuncomfortable, I want you to tell me.
但你觉得我没问题
But you don't think there'sabcsomething wrong with me.
不 宝贝 他们测试你是为了帮爸爸
No, baby, they'reabctesting you to help daddy.
是的 你所做的很重要
Yes, what you're doing is very important.
你做得越好 我们就越了解你爸爸
It's likthe better you do,abcthe better we know your dad is.
先从热开始
I'll start with heat.
这不是他的错
I know it's not his fault.
他不是故意那样说的 但于事无补
I know what he says isabcinvoluntary, but it doesn't help.
内心深处 他还是他
Inside,he's still the same man.
问题就在这儿
That's the problem.
很显然他有这些想法很长时间了
Apparently he's beenabcthinking this stuff all along.
不管"他"是谁 都不是我当初想嫁的男人
Whoever that "same man" is, it's notabcthe person I thought I was married to.
你还好吗?
You okay?
她这会儿该有感觉了
She should be feeling something by now.
这说明什么? 她也病了?
What does that mean? Is she sick too?
Marika! 甜心!
Marika! Honey!
你烧伤了 为什么一开始不告诉我?
You're burned. Why didn'tabcyou tell me it started to hurt?
我想帮爸爸
I wanted to help daddy.
你说我做得越好 爸爸就越好
You said the better I do,abcthe better daddy has to be.
抱歉
Sorry.
我饿了
I'm starving.
这样我们才能试验
Only way we can do the test.
幸好是你 而不是Hadley医生
Good thing it's you and not dr. Hadley.
能让她别靠近我吗?
Could you keep her away from me?
我对生活富有想象
I have a rich imaginative life.
可不想到处分享
I'd rather not share it.
我们都有
We all have thoughts.
我知道我们都有性幻想
I know we all have sexual thoughts.
龌龊的想法
We have ignoble thoughts.
我只是不想人们从我的想法推断我的人品abc特别不希望我老婆这么想
I just don't want those to be who I amabcto people, especially not to my wife.
明白 用一闪而过的想法abc给人定性是不公正的
I understand. I don't think it would beabcfair to define me by my passing thoughts.
行动就是选择
My real choices are my actions.
我不会做任何事来伤害她
And I've never done anything to hurt her.
我没有外遇
I've never cheated.
- 不是吧 你有外遇?abc- 什么?
- You're kidding me. You've cheated?abc- What?
没有 你怎么问这个?
No. Why would you say that?
因为你看着很内疚
Because you look guilty as hell.
你是认真的?
Are you serious?
当然是认真的
Of course you're serious.
是 大家都知道
Yes, everyone knows.
天 他们肯定以为你是个卑鄙小人
God, they must think you're a creep.
他们不知道 他们可能是白痴
They might not know. They might be idiots.
我只是说说
Just say these things.
干嘛把我叫这儿来?
Why'dou page me here?
报告病人的情况
I need you to update me onabcthe patient's condition.
看着像死了
Seems to be dead.
干吗把我叫这儿来?
Why'd you page me here?
一边朝墙上打这个 一边报告病人情况
I need you to update me on the patient'sabccondition while hitting this against the wall.
只有这儿能两者都干
This is the only place we can do both.
刚抽完最后一次血
I finished the last blood draw.
我希望跟我的人有些挑战精神
I expect the people who workabcfor me to rise to a challenge.
除非不想在我手下干
Unless they don't expect to work for me.
最后一次抽血是在早上六点
Last blood draw was at 6:00 A. M.
整晚糖水平未上一百二
Sugar levels neverabcrose above 120 all night.
说明葡萄糖正常
So the glucose was normal.
糖尿病的理论错误
Means you were wrong about diabetes.
我还是认为是内分泌疾病abc可能是搞错了腺体
Itill think it's the endocrine system.abcMaybe I just got the wrong gland.
查完胰腺查甲状腺? 有道理
So you're going for thyroid insteadabcpancreas? Makes sense.
好 我再不和Wilson去打墙球了
Fine. I'm not playingabcracquetball with wilson.
我没和Wilson打墙球
I was never playingabcracquetball with wilson.
我从没和Wilson打过墙球
I have never playedabcracquetball with wilson.
我只是认为abc有个部门头头欠我人情挺好
I thought it would be helpful ifabca department head owed me a favor.
但不值得这个
But it's not worth this.
不坏嘛 你演得不错 长进了
Not bad. You put on aabcgood show. You studied up.
Wilson的确预定了场地
Wilson actually booked a court.
但如果你真会打墙球abc就会发现你拿的是壁球拍
If you were really a racquetball player, you'dabcknow that you were holding a squash racket.
让Kutner做甲状腺摄取扫描abc你去候诊室打个盹
Tell kutner to doa thyroid reuptake scan,abcthen go grab a nap in one of the on-call rooms.
接着去做一个甲状腺摄取扫描abc我们认为--
We're taking you to do a thyroidabcreuptake scan.We think your--
等你解释清楚了为何我女儿abc手上绑着绷带再走
I'm not going a until you explain whyabcmy daughter has a bandage on her hand.
你说你想做试验
You just said youabcwanted to run some test.
我要是知道她会受伤abc我肯定说"见鬼 不"
I'd known it would involveabcpain,I'd have said, "hell, no."
只是轻微烫伤
It's a mild burn.
Marika可能和你一样有神经疾病abc我们想确定--
Since marika has a neurological disabilityabclike you, we needed to make sure--
她没有病
She has no disality.
Nick 你知道她有听觉处理问题
Nk, you know about herabcproblem with auditory processing.
"听觉处理"?
"Auditory processing"?
这好比在说 abc"我不能容忍我女儿不是最棒的"
That's code for "I can't standabcthinking my daughter's not perfect."
专家说Marika的测试分数--
The therapistabcsaid marika's test scores--
不确定 她不是残疾
Were indeterminate.Sheabcdoesn't have a disability.
她是做白日梦
She day dreams.
她的分数低于平均值abc是因为她低于平常
She gets below-average marks inabcschool because she's below average.
大人都想孩子"高于平均分"
Every parent thinks theirabcchild's "above average."
Nick!
你知道平均值的含义吗?
Do you have any idea whatabcthe word average means?
总有人得在它之下
Somebody asto be under it.
Nick 闭嘴
Nick, shut up.
噢 甜心...
Oh, honey...
我不是说你笨
I'm not saying you're stupid.
你母亲不是最拔尖的 但她也做得很好
Your mother's not the sharpest crayonabcin the box, and she does great.
看见了吗 这就是为什么abc我要你妈让你呆在家
See, this is why I told yourabcmother to keep you at home.
不想你来
Didn't want you here.
Marika!
Marika 等等! 她...
Marika, wait! Get her...
你发烧了
You're burning up.
肺部充满积液 得马上抽出来
And your lungs are full ofabcfluid. We need to get it out.
来两百毫克呋塞米 两毫克吗啡 快
I need 200 milligrams of furosemideabcand two milligrams of morphine,stat.
他体温上升到了103华氏(摄氏39.4)
His temperature is 103.
感染
Infection.
肯定是类固醇加重了感染
The steroids must haveabcforced it into the open.
什么种类的感染? 可能是任何情况
What kind of infection?abcIt could be anything.
金葡球菌 肺结核 线虫...
Staph aureus,tuberculosis,abcstrongyloides...
去问Phineas 找到病史
Go back to phineas,get a history.
问过了 他没出过国
We've got a history. He hasn'tabcbeen out of the country.
详细点
Get a detailed history.
工作地和家里都没病人
No one at home is sick.abcNo one at work is sick.
没有虱子或蚊子
There's no sign of ticks or mosquitoes.
还要更详细 再问
Get a more detailedabchistory. Ask him again.
再问再问直到他想起什么abcKutner去
And againuntil he remembersabcsomething. Not you. Kutn can do it.
你还有别的事忙
You're gonna be busy with something else.
我邀请你去吃午饭
I'm here to invite you to lunch.
呃 为什么?
Uh, why?
我是被迫的
I've been made.
House让我来当双面间谍
House sent me back toabcyou as a double agent.
有什么毛病吗?
Anything wrong?
眼睛有点红
Eyes are a little red.
可真震惊
There's a shocker.
自从进了这儿 我就没睡过好觉
I haven't had a good night'sabcsleep since this thing started.
你该去休息一下
You should get some rest yourself.
好主意 这会花些时间
That's a good idea. Thisabcis going to take some time.
检查得相当彻底
It'll be pretty exhaustive.
你是怕说出什么的时候我在场?
Are you afraid of what youabcmight say while I'm here?
是
Yes.
你是说还有比我听过的更糟的?
Are you telling me there's somethingabcworse than what I've already heard?
不 我-我不知道我会说出什么来
No, I-I don't know what I'm gonna say.
我不知道下次会怎样伤害你
I don't know how I'm gonna hurt you next.
我想我们最好还是分开一下
I think we should be around eachabcother as little as possible right now.
真可悲
This is pathetic.
我知道
I know.
告诉Marika我非常爱她
Tell marika I love her very much.
她明白的
S understands that.
我想她没有
I don't think she does.
你这么说是想让我感觉好些
You're just saying that toabcmake me feel better.
是的
Yeah.
无聊的生活 总呆在家里
Guy leads a boring life.abcThey stay home a lot.
不旅行 没外来宠物 家附近没死水
No travel,no exotic pets,abcno nearby standing water.
听起来你有点高兴 直接跳主题行不?
You sound pleased about something.abcCan we get to that part?
他妻子拯救狗
His wife rescues dogs.
往家里带回过一条罗特维尔犬
Among others, a big rottweiler who'sabctaken over the house.
病人很讨厌它
Our patient hates it.
- 妻子也听到了?abc- 没
- Was the wife there to hear is?abc- No.
太坏了 继续
Too bad. Keep going.
这只狗在每间屋子都留下痕迹
The dog marks his territory allabcover the living room.
我问他有没可能他把水或食物abc放在狗能碰到的地方
I asked what the odds were that he would haveabcput down food or drink where the dog could reach.
他说修电视的时候 他放了杯果汁在地上
He said he put a glass of juice on theabcfloor while he was fixingthe television.
- 狗修电视?abc- 嗯
- The dog was fixing the television?abc- Y.
- 病人眼睛红了?abc- 嗯
- The patient's eyes red?abc- Yeah.
我想可能是韦耳氏病abc(牛钩端螺旋体病)
I'm thinking weil's.
细菌 他运气好 用强力霉素
Bacterial. He lucked out.abcStart him on doxycycline.
要是好转了 那我们就是对的
If he improves,we'll know we were right.
我告诉了Wilson你派我去刺探情报
I told wilson you sentabcme to get information.
然后你又告诉我
And now you're telling me.
你想成什么 四面间谍?
What does that make you,a quadruple agent?
他让我把他的电邮打印出来
He let me print out his e-mails.
很好 他想我们知道的情报
Excellent. Informationabche wants us to have.
- 他让你打印删除的邮件没?abc- 没
- Did he let you printabcout his deleted e-mails? - No.
那就回去--
Then goabcback there--
我坐在那儿的时候 我想不妨打出来吧
As long as I was sitting there,abcI thought I'd print 'em anyway.
最上面那个就是你要找的
Top one's the one you're looking for.
"确认周三晚上七点的会面"
Writing to confirmabcwednesday at 7:00 P.M."
发送给jgonzalez@nymcy.net
It's out goingto jgonzalez@nymcy. Net.
有位肿瘤学家叫Joan Gonzalez
There's a joan gonzalez in oncology.
是会诊
It's a consult.
秘密会诊 晚上七点
Secret consult,7:00 P.
Joan可真精神
Oh, joan is perky.
你错了 还附带了病历的
You're wrong. There was aabcpatient file attached.
哪?
Where?
- 有密码abc- 不对
- It wasabcpassword-protected. - No.
Wilson从不会给病历上密码
Wilson doesn'tabcpassword-protect his patient files.
他知道只有我会去刺探
I'm the only one he'dabcexpect ever to look there,
也知道我想查的是谁
and he knows there's onlyabcone patient I'd want to check on.
你认为Wilson病了?
You think wilson's sick?
如果Wilson得了癌症abc他没理由开三小时车去曼哈顿
If wilson had cancer,there'd be no reasonabcfor him to drive three hours to manhattan.
他在这儿能悄悄得到最好治疗
He could pull strings here andabcget the best trement.
Gonzalez有六篇论文
Six articles by gonzalez.
"关于肿瘤病人的自杀思想"
"Managing suicidalabcthoughts in oncology patients,"
"白血病患儿的自杀思维"
"suicidal ideation inabcchildren with leukemia."
我不想问的 但你察觉到他消沉吗?
I don't want to ask this,but have you everabchad reason to think he might be depressed?
没 出去
No. Get out of here.
烧退了 肺也干净了
Your fever's down andabcyour lungs are clearing.
要多久大脑问题才能解决?
How long before thisabcbrain thing goes away?
感染是治好了 但感染带来的伤害...
The infection's gone, butabcthe damage the infection did...
只能终身为伴
you'll have to live with.
你是说没法好了?
You're telling me you can't fix this?
肯定有办法的
There's gotta be a way.
我们需要把扣带回上的损伤移除
We'd need to remove the damagedabcarea in our cingulate gyrus,
但风险极大 因为靠近脑干
buit's too close toabcthe brainstem to risk surgery.
你们不敢冒险
You can't risk it.
我可以去找更好的医院 更好的医生--
But I could shop around, and mae someabcbetter doctors at a better hospital--
脑干控制了躯体的自主神经系统
The brain stem ntrols theabcbody's involuntary systems.
很小的错误都可能害死你
The slightest mistake could kill you.
就算幸免 你有可能永远无法自主呼吸
Even if you survive, you may neverabcbe able to breathe on your own again.
- 可能永远不能--abc- 我知道了
- You may never--abc- I get it.
我知道你现在还接受不了
I know this seems like aabclot to deal with right now.
但不少神经系统有缺陷的人都能逐渐适应
But people have adapted to livingabcwith all kinds of neurologica deficits.
嗨 至少我们能保证不会更糟
Hey, at least we can promise youabcit won't get any worse.
给我滚出去
Get the hell out of my room.
你的助手说你到医院外去散步
Your assistant said that you wereabcout of the hospital, taking a walk.
有紧急情况吗?
Is there an emergency?
不知道 有吗?
I don't know. Is there?
除非有事要想 不然你从不散步
You never take a walk unless you'veabcgot something you need to think about.
或许你对我散步意图的统计数据错误
Maybe you just don't have a goodabcstatistical samplin of my walks.
当你需要思考时abc会做的另一件事就是到我办公室
The other thing you do when you needabcto think is you come to my office.
显然这桩事abc你只能同纽约的那个Gonzalez商量
Apparently, this is something you can onlyabcdiscuss with gonzalez at new york mercy.
Taub
Taub.
又一个House学校毕业的侦探
Another graduate of the houseabcschool of being a dick.
私家侦探
Private dick.
听着 我很想能让你全面审讯abc但现在我只想要杯热咖啡
Look, I'd love to stay for the fullabcinquisition, but I need some hot coffee.
你当然需要热咖啡
Of course you need hot coffee.
外面才45度(摄氏7.22度)abc你却没拿大衣
It's 45 degrees outside,andabcyou left your coat upstairs.
为什么呢?
Why?
你准备告诉我为什么我会忘了大衣?
You're going to tellabcme why I forgot my coat?
出门的时候 寒冷会提醒你
Once you get outside, thecoldabcwould have reminded you.
你能折回来拿 但是却没有
You could have come back,but you didn't.
你选择冻着
You chose to be uncomfortable.
为什么会选这个?
Why would someone choose that?
因为恨自己?
Because they hate themselves?
有没想过你不知道的事并不意味挑战?
Has it ever occurred to you that when don't shareabcsomething, it might notbe meant as a challenge?
我只是希望生活中abc能有一处免受你的探究
It might just mean that I'd like there to beoneabcmolecule of my life that goes unexaminedby gregory house.
我是Nick Greenwaldabc听说你是我的主治医师
Nick greenwald. I hearabcyou're the guy in charge.
我就是那个大脑抑制功能失调的患者
I'm the patient with the disinhibition.
若是道谢的话就免了 走吧
If you're here to sayabcthanks,you're welcome. Now go away.
我才不是来致谢的abc我快气坏了
Oh, I'm not thankful. I'm pissed.
那你就更应该离开了
Oh, all the more reason to go away.
他们想让我出院回家
They're talking about sending me home.
我能去哪? 我只会赶走那些关心我的人?
To what? A life where I'll continually driveabcaway anyone who might for a second care about me?
的确是个问题
Those are the brakes.
你可以帮我做手术
You could operate.
你会死
You could die.
我要好不了 就死了算了
So I'm either better or dead?
我可以接受
I'm okay with that.
我 一直是个急躁的人
I-I've always been kindabcof A... an impatient guy.
可我一直拼命管住我的嘴巴
But I've worked hard to keep my mth shut.
让我的妻子开心 让我女儿开心
I've made my wife happy. I'veabcmade my little girl happy.
我想要回这种生活
I want that back.
不然 活着也没意思
Otherwise, it's no life.
我想你动个小手术
I want you to remove small problem.
我不是神经外科医生
I'm not a neuro surgeon.
可是你的老板是 你可以协助他
But your boss is. You could assist.
我保证这会是你履历上光辉的一页
I'm sure you'd like toabcadd to your resume.
离脑干太近了 没人敢做
It's too near the brainabcstem. Nobody's gonna touch it.
你的上司敢 他是个自大狂
Your boss would. He's an egomaniac.
我一直在俱乐部见到他 所以知道
I know 'cause I keepabcseeing him at the club.
他只需要别人再煽煽风
He just needs a little push.
我确信你把他捧得挺乐
I'm sure by now you'veabckissed his ass sufficiently.
你想让我改口说你官场悟性高?
Would you like me to phrase itabcas "you're politically gifted"?
我就赞下你何妨
I can do that.
你想我帮忙
You want me to help you?
告诉我原因
Tell me why.
- 什么原因?abc- 你如此重视的原因
- Why what?abc- Why you care.
问题解决了 那人不会死的
The puzzle's solved. The guy's alive.
手术完 情况不比目前糟糕就谢天谢地了
And the odds of coming out of this surgeryabcwith that same status weren't that great.
病人现在生活没有质量
My patient has a quality of life issue.
不过是嘴巴臭
He says awful things.
几乎不算病
Hardly a medical condition.
如果就这样出院 他迟早会失去家庭
When he leaves here,he'sabcgoing to lose his family.
他会让同事敬而远之
He's gonna alienate theabcpeople he works with.
如果找到朋友愿意忍受他的胡言乱语abc就算幸运了
And if he ever fdsa friend who's willingabcto put up with his crap, he'll be lucky.
可迟早会把他们也气走
Until he drives them away too.
我试试吧
I'll see what I can do.
这回不出门就穿大衣
You've apparently got thisabcwhole coat thing backwards.
我大概反应过度了
I may have over reacted.
毫无疑问
You definitely overreacted.
- 我就知道瞒不过你abc- 事有蹊跷
- I knew you'd meet me halfway.abc- It made me think.
你的软肋莫过于失去某人
You only snap on oneabcsubject: Losing people.
所以我重新搜索了
So I went back to the intel.
纽约慈善医院确实abc只有一个医生叫Gonzalez
It's true there's only one doctorabcnamed gonzalez at new york mercy,
可是精神科病房也有个abc叫Javier gonzalez的护士
but there's a javier gonzalezabcwho's a nurse in the psych ward.
你有什么亲人会在那里?
And who could youabclose who'd end up there?
我不告诉你大概是因为你总能猜中
Maybe the reason I don't always openabcup to you is because it's redundant.
Daniel wilson.
只要名字对了 打个电话就不难查明一切
Once you got a name,it's amazing howabcmuch stuff you can learn on the phone.
还能利用医生身份abc特别我还精于撒谎
I mean, if you're aabcdoctor and you lie freely.
你弟弟在曼哈顿abc一间办公楼的大堂过夜被发现
They found your brother sleeping in theabclobby of an office buiing in manhattan.
当被要求离开时他反抗abc警察把他送进了慈善医院的精神科
Got aggressive when they asked him to leave,abcand e cops took him to the mercy psych ward.
自从他离家abc又有几种新的精神科药物问世
There have been new anti-psychoticsabcdeveloped since he ran away.
这几天他都在服药
He's been on them for a couple of days.
今晚他应该能够和我聊聊了
And by tonight, he shouldabcbe in shape to talk to me.
但你不知道他是否想见你
But you're not sure if he wants to.
几个小时后 我就会在纽约abc到时就都清楚了
I'll be in new york in a fewabchours. I guess I'll find out.
为啥你不告诉我?
Why wouldn't you tell me this?
House 我们...
House, you and I...
我们之间没有正常的社会契约
we don't have the normal social contract.
我得不到你的好言相慰
I don't expect you toabctell me the lies--
我绝对能撒谎哄你
I am fully capable of lying to you.
我撒谎不止一次了
I've lied plenty of times.
我是指心知肚明的谎言
I mean, collaborative lies.
当有人需要被骗时 就帮帮他吧
Giving someone a hand who maybe needs toabcdeceive themselves just a little.
这两天我一直在想abcDanny看到我会有什么反应
For two days I've been thinking aboutabchow danny's gonna react when he sees me.
如果我向别人诉说 他们都会说
If I said that toabcanybody else,they'd say,
"别担心 一切都会好起来的"
"don't worry.It'll all be all right."
可你不会
You wodn't.
因为事实极有可能与之相反
Because it might all go horribly wrong.
对
Yeah.
是的 很有可能
Yeah, it might.
如果是这样 你需要有人陪你去
In which case,youabcmight want some company.
心跳未停止 过了第一关
Your heart's beating. First hurdle past.
现在来看看你能否自主呼吸
Now we need know if youabccan breathe for yourself.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank god.
知道你是谁吗?
Now, do you know who you are?
我是Nick Greenwald 曾是个混球
Nick green wald. Former S.O.B.
谢谢
Thank you.
终于可以和我的爱妻重新过美好生活了
Now I can go back to my beautifulabclife with my beautiful wife.
我冒了生命危险动手术abc也许她就能少点怨气 让我轻松一阵
Maybe she'll stop whining and cut meabcsome slack now that I've risked my life.
这不对 病灶已经切除
Doesn't make sense.abcWe removed the problem.
我们是切除了病灶abc也许诊断错了
We removed the damage. Maybeabcwe were wrong about the problem.
我希望我们能渡过这一关
I need to believe weabccan get through this.
体温94.5 (摄氏34.7°)
Temperature's 94.5
你真的觉得我很蠢?
Do you really think I'm stupid?
亲爱的 你不是蠢 你只不过--拜托别这样
Honey, you're not stupid. You'abcjust-- please don't do this.
这可能是手术造成的
It could be the effect of the surgery.
Nick 难道你一点也不尊重我abc你认同我的工作吗?
Do you at least respect me,nick whatabcdo you think of what I do for a living?
我觉得那些宣称自己了不得的人
I think people whoabcpublice important things are people
其实干不了大事
who can't do importantabcthings themselves.
亲爱的 够了 别哭
Honey, stop. Don't.
- 你后悔娶了我吗?abc- 94.2 (摄氏34.5°)
- Do you regret marrying me?abc- 94.2
- 人们总会时不时怀疑abc- 拿张电热毯来
- Sometimes.Everybody wonders--abc- Get me a heating blanket.
- 你有没有爱过我?abc- 当然
- Do you even love me?abc- Yes.
我都弄不清为什么
I don't know why.
等等 听我说--
Aud,abcwait.Let me--
出现V波 拿除颤仪来
V-tach. Get me the paddles.
走开
Clear.
心电图显示心脏很正常
Echo says his heart is structurally fine.
可他的体温一直在降
But his temperature is still dropping.
体温很快就会过低
He's headed for hypothermia.
House不接电话 转到语音留言去了
I can't reach house. Itabcjust goes to voicemail.
就是说他不是感染咯
It means we were wrong about infection.
体温忽高忽低abc说明他的体温调节点出事了
His temperature's just going up and downabcbecause something's playing with his thermostat.
也就是说大脑病变扩散了
Which means the brainabcdamage is spreading.
什么会同时引起大脑受损 流鼻血abc还有肺 心脏及肾的病变?
What causes brain damage and nosebleeddabcinvolves the lungs, heart and kidneys?
肿瘤? 辅助检查可以确诊
Cancer? We could text him.
不是肿瘤 前列腺特异性抗原abc血涂片及肠镜均未见异常
It's not cancer normal psa, normalabcblood smear,colonoscopy normal.
做个全身的扫描吧
Do a full body scan.
House最恨全身扫描
House hates full body scans.
- House不在abc- House是对的
- House isn't here.abc- House is right.
人人做全身扫描都会发现一些异常
Everybody's got three or four meaninglessabcanomalies that'll come up on a scan.
揪着这些不放只会浪费时间
Chasing each one willabctake time we don't have.
想通后就给他做个全身扫描
Feel free to send him an im.
你说你有一次见过你弟弟
You told me you saw your brother once.
在他失踪后
After he disappeared.
13年前
13 years ago.
我曾经疯了似的去普林斯顿
I used to go toabcprinceton whenever I could.
把每个收容所都找遍了
I must have hit everyabchomeless shelter in town.
然后有一天我在餐厅吃三明治
And then one day,I'm just sittingabcat this deli, having a sandwich,
我发现他站在窗外
I look out the window, and there he is.
出去时他已经走了
He was gone by the time I got outside.
所以当我告诉你abc普里斯顿医院招人你立刻就来了
That's why you wereo eager when Iabctold you there was a job at princeton.
还以为是因为我呢
I thought it was just my charm.
小鸭子的电话 不接吗?
That's the team. Shouldn't you answer?
他们发来短信 说他们又去干蠢事了
They already texted me toabcs they're doing something stupid.
腹部有个很小的动脉瘤
There's a small abdominal eurysm.
这不相关 还有什么?
Irrelevant. What else you got?
脏胸膜有个囊肿
Cyst in the pleura around the lungs.
也不相关 不会导致症状
Also irrelevant. Couldn'tabccause any of the sympts.
肝脏有个高密度点abc可能是个血管畸形
There's a density in the liver.abcCould be vascular malformation.
如果是多发性动静脉畸形abc血流增多就能引起这些症状
If he's got multiple avms, screwed-upabcblood flow would explain erything.
只有做血管造影确诊了
We can only spot them with angiography.
做对照靶扫描 把病点栓塞了
We'll have to do targeted scans withabccontrast and then embolize each one.
能赶在他体温过低前完成吗?
Can we do that before he freezes?
试试吧
We'll find out.
Kutner手机的拼写检查器自作聪明
The spell-correct on kutner'sabcphone has got a hair trigger.
要不然 就是病人的花花肺里刮起了龙卷风
Either that, or the patient has aabccyclone in the floral of his lungs.
你不穿大衣abc在45度(7摄氏°)的天气外出散步
You took a walk in 45-degree weather,abcand you left your coat behind.
继续说
Go ahead.
我觉得你是在自我惩罚
I think you were punishing yourself.
你想体验一下在新泽西的冬天abc无家可归的感觉
I think you wanted to feel what it wouldabcbe like be homeless a new jersey winter.
这说明你很内疚
That tells me guilt.
我猜你肯定出了什么事
That tells me something happened.
他十几岁就患上精神分裂症
The schizophreniaabcstarted when he was a teenager.
那时他还在上大学
When he was in college.
他有服药 但他还是觉得考试得Babc教授会不放过他
He was on meds,but he'd still think aabcprofessor was out to get him because he got a b,
他从不洗澡 所以和舍友吵架
or he'd fight with hisabcroommates because he never showered.
- 你那时在哪?abc- 医学院
- Where were you?abc- Med school.
他每天都打电话给我abc一说就是数小时
He called me everyabcday. Talked for hours.
我哪有时间
I didn't have hours.
有趣
Interesting.
迟点再说这个 你继续
Later for that. Go on.
我受够了每个人都把我当知心姐姐abc所以一天当他打电话来--
I was tiredof being the guy that everybodyabccounted on,so one night, danny called--
那晚 他在电话里哭着抱怨什么
one night, danny called,crying,abcupset about something.
可我必须准备考试
I had to study for an exam.
所以我挂了他的电话...
So I-I hung up...
拿上东西去了图书馆abc我不想再听到电话响
ok my things. I went to the library  soabcI wouldn't have to hear the phone ring.
后来怎么样
I wonderhow that turned out.
第二天我妈打来电话
My mother called me the next day.
Danny离家出走了 没有带药
Danny had run away andabcleft his meds behind.
所以我知道他根本没有能力回来
Which I knew meant that he wouldabcnever be able to choose to come back,
因为他不能融入现实社会
because he'd be so detached from reality.
你在大学里 尝试过一次abc做个正常的自私鬼
So you made your one effort toabclive a normal, selfish life,
就马上被天打雷劈
and the universeabcimmediately smacked you down.
我们总是倾向于在随机事件里找规律
Anbecause we're wired to findabcmeaning in semi-random events,
所以你决定永远不再犯同样的错
you decided never toabcbe that careless again.
你不觉得这是自然而然的吗?
You don't think that's a little facile?
我不觉得
Actually, I don't.
你是刻意这么做
I think you did it consciously.
你就像奥运会运动员训练似的abc把自己塑造成好好先生
You developed your people-pleasing talents theabcway an olympic athlete develops his muscles.
你对偶发事件反应过度了
Talk about an overreaction toabca single event.
但事态很严重
It was a pretty big event.
挂电话?
Hanging up the phone?
这就是你不断自责的原因
That's what you're blaming all this on.
是你拼命想纠正的行为
That's the behavior you'veabcbeen trying to correct.
好像你弟弟除此以外没别的困扰
As though nothing elseabcwent wrong in your brother'life.
当然他也反应过度了 可是...
Of course,he overreacted too but...
血糖是正常的
his glucose was normal.
我们不是在说我弟弟了 是吗?
We're not talking about myabcbrother anymore, are we?
我是House 动静脉畸形解释不了血糖
It's house. Adms don'tabcexplain his glucose.
这是我人生中至关重要的一刻...
Since this is significant momentabcin my life and all...
- 没错abc- 我就要进去了
- Yeah.abc- I think I'll just go in then.
- 说详细点abc- 没错
- Explain that.abc- Right.
你给他用了类固醇abc血糖应该会升高
You'd given him steroids. Hisabcglucose should have been elevated.
那可能是全身扫描发现的囊肿引起的
That wannabe cyst youabcfound in the whole body scan,
撇开血糖 那只是个囊肿
without the glucose,it'sabcan irrelevant cyst.
可和血糖挂上 那就是个纤维瘤
With the glucose,it'sabca relevant fibroma.
他有doege-potter综合症abc(纤维瘤引起的低血糖症)
He has doege-potter syndrome.
纤维瘤分泌生长激素abc就像胰岛素 起降血糖作用
His fibroma is secreting human growth hormone,abcwhich acts like insulin,wering his glucose.
可解释不了器官功能失调及大脑病变
It doesn't explain theabcorgan failure orhe brain damage.
这是机体的过度反应
This whole thing is an overreaction.
小小的纤维瘤
That one small fibroma.
尽管是良性的abc但机体把它当成入侵者了
It's benign, but hisabcby'sacting like it's an invader.
抗体开始攻击它abc同时也攻击其他系统
His antibodies went to war against it andabcgot carried away,attack his other systems.
切除纤维瘤abc他很快就会回复那个开心的伪君子
Take out the froma, he'll be aabchappy hypocrite again in no time.
可能我需要叫出租车
Maybe I should call a cab.
- 你妻子可能只是迟了点abc- 或许
- Your wife's probably just late.abc- Yeah.
我很抱歉...
I'm sorry about...
你也知道... 我说的那些事
you know... the things I said.
我的鼻子很大
I have a copicuous nose.
但和你的脸很配
It suits your face.
抱歉我来晚了 堵车
I'm sorry I'm late. Traffic.
好消息
I have some good news.
我原想告诉你 但你病了
I was gonna tell you,andabcthen you got sick.
时机不对
It didn't seem like the best time.
我升职了
I've been offered a better position.
我会统筹三个城市的抗癌步行活动
I'd be coordinating cancerabcareness walks in three cities.
太好了 祝贺你
That's great. Congratulations.
我知道你一直很努力
I know you've worked hard for this.
谢谢
Thank you.
Marika还好吗?
Is marika okay?
她不生气了
I'm sure she's moved on.
小孩总是比较容易恢复的
Kids are so resilient.
你还好吗?
You okay?
下周我还会去看Danny
I'll be seeing danny again next week.
- 我希望你也去见他abc- 当然 他挺逗的
- I'd like you to meet him.abc- Sure. He sounds interesting.
继续说
Go on.
我以为再次见到他会改变许多事
I thought seeing himabcagain would change everything.
也许是好事 也可能是坏事
It would be wonderful or terrible.
可... 我们就像陌生人
Instead... we're just strangers.
这好像有点虎头蛇尾
It's kind of anticlimactic.
总比坏事强吧
Which is better than terrible.
继续说
Go on.
我们之间没有社会契约abc你会不会觉得很困惑?
Does it bother you thatabcwhave no social contract?
我一生都在妥协
My whole life is one big compromise.
我小心翼翼 仿佛别人都是瓷做的
I tiptoe around everyone likeabcthey're made of china.
我一直在琢磨:abc如果我这么说会不会有什么后果?
I spend all my time analyzing: Whatabcwill the effect be if I say this?
然后你出现了abc你这个愤世嫉俗的家伙.
Then there's you.abcYou're a reality junkie.
如果我说善意的谎言 你反而会倒打一耙
If I offered you a comforting lie,abcyou'd smack me over the head with it.
这样还不差
Let's not change that.
好啊
Kay.
不 如果你依照正常的社交规矩
No, see, this-- if you wereabcimplementing the social contract,
你这么说 只是因为...
you'd say that, but only because...
你想我好过些...
it makes me feel better...
看着你自相矛盾abc真是太逗了
It is kind of fun watchingabcyou torture yourself.
- 你觉得我和我弟的关系会有改善吗?abc- 不觉得
- Do you think things will work out with my brother?abc- No.
就算事情弄砸了 也不是你的错
But when it does go wrong,abcit won't be your fault.
谢了 House.
Thanks, house.
其实你挺喜欢怪物卡车的
You doactually like monster trucks.
当然
Aolutely.